Thomas Foxen Anderson Papers 1928-1989 Mss.Ms.Coll.75
American Philosophical Society
- Series IV. Works by Anderson, 1943-1985; 14 boxes; 6.5 linear feet
  - "Some Fundamental Limitations to the Preservation of Three-Dimensional Specimens for the Electron Microscope", [1954] (Box 38)
    -See also Ser.I, The New York Academy of Sciences
    -See also Ser.VII, "Some Fundamental Limitatons to the Preservation of Three-Dimensional Specimens for the Electron Microscope"
  - "Some Kinetic Theories of Bacterial Motility", n.d. (Box 38)
  - "Some Properties of Color Film in the Electron Microscope", 1956 (Box 38)
  - "Some Reactivation of Antiserum-Neutralized Bacteriophage T3"--with A.H. Doermann, [1952] (Box 38)
  - "Some Recent Developments in the Electron Microscopy of Viruses"--Lecture, 16 May 1952 (Box 38)
  - "Specific Agglutination of Phages and Polio Virus by Antibody Molecules as Seen in the Electron Microscope"--with Nobuto Yamamoto and Klaus Hummeler (abstract), [1961] (Box 38)
  - "Specimen Preparation"--Lecture, 1946 (Box 38)
  - "The Spermatazoon and Fertilization Membrane of Arbacia Punctulata as Shown by the Electron Microscope"--with Ethel Browne Harvey, [1943] (Box 38)
  - "The Spreading of One Liquid on the Surface of Another", n.d. (Box 38)
  - "Stereoscopic Electron Microscopy of Biological Materials", [1951] (Box 38)
  - "Stereoscopic Electron Microscopy of Phage Particles and of Their Interactions with Host Cells"--Abstract, 1953 (Box 38)
  - "Stereoscopic Studies of Bacteriophage Systems with the Electron Microscope", 1953 (Box 38)
  - "Stereoscopic Studies of Cells and Viruses in the Electron Microscope", [1952] (Box 38)
  - "Stéréoscopie et Résolution en Microscopie Électronique", 1957 (Box 38)
  - "Structural Abnormalities on the Surface of Epidermoid Carcinoma Cells", 1955 (Box 38)
  - "Structural Differentiation within the Bacterial Cell as Shown by the Electron Microscope"--with Stuart Mudd and Katherine Polevitzky, 1940 (Box 38)
  - "Structure and Function of Bacterial Viruses"--Lecture at Pennsylvania State University, Apr. 1960 (Box 38)
  - "Structure and Function of Bacteriophage P1 and Its Morphological Variants" (Box 38)
    -See Ser.V, Walker, Donald H., Jr., author and Thomas F. Anderson, supervisor, same title
  - "The Structure and Function of Bacteriophages"--Lecture at Temple University, 1 Mar. 1962 (Box 38)
  - "Structure and Genetic Properties of Bacterial Viruses", 1963 (Box 38)
  - "Structure and Function of Viruses"--Lecture, 1965 (Box 38)
  - "The Structure and Organization of the Bacterial Cell as Shown by Electron Microscopy"--with Stuart Mudd and Katherine Polevitzky (abstract), 1944 (Box 38)
  - "Structure of Bacteriophage as Related to Adsorption on Host Bacteria"--Seminar at Johnson Foundation, 28 Jun. 1958 (Box 38)
  - "The Structure of Certain Biological Specimens Prepared by the Critical Point Method", 1952 (Box 38)
  - "The Structure of Normal and Contracted Tail Sheaths of T4 Bacteriophage"--with Sam Krimm, 1966 (Box 38)
  - "The Structure of Viruses"--Lecture, 1960-1962 (Box 38)
  - "Structure of Type 5 Adenovirus II. Fine Structure of Virus Subunits. Morphologic Relationship of Structural Subunits to Virus Specific Soluble Antigens from Infected Cells"--with Wesley C. Wilcox and Harold S. Ginsberg, 1963 (Box 38)
    -See also Ser.V, Ginsberg, Harold S., "Structure of Type 5 Adenovirus I. Antigenic..."
    -See also Ser.VII, "Structure of Type 5 Adenovirus II. Fine..."
  - "Structures of Bacteriophages and Their Variations"--with Nobuto Yamamoto and Donald H. Walker, Jr. (abstract), 1961 (Box 38)
  - "Studies of Viruses with the Electron Microscope"--Abstract, n.d. (Box 38)
  - "Studies with the Electron Microscope"--Abstract, 17 Mar. 1942 (Box 38)
  - "A Study by Means of the Electron Microscope of the Reaction Between Tobacco Mosaic Virus and Its Antiserum"--with Wendell M. Stanley, 1941 (Box 38)
  - "The Study of Colloids with the Electron Microscope". Folder #1, [1942] (Box 39)
    -See also Ser.IV, same title
  - "The Study of Colloids with the Electron Microscope". Folder #2, [1942] (Box 39)
  - "A Study of the Effects of Ultraviolet Irradiation on the Pathogenicity of the Crown Gall Organism", n.d. (Box 39)
  - "A Study of Thiobacillus Thiooxidans with the Electron Microscope"--with W.W. Umbreit, [1942] (Box 39)
  - "Summary of Proceedings of the 1952 UNESCO Conference on Bacteriophage", 1942 (Box 39)
  - "Summary of the Report on the Effects of Radiation on Microorganisms", Mar. 1938 (Box 39)
  - "Sur les Processus de Conjugaison et de Recombinaison Chez Escherichia Coli. III. Aspects Morphologiques en Microscopie Électronique"--with Elie L. Wollman and François Jacob, [1957] (Box 39)
    -See also Ser. VII, same title
  - "The Surface Structure of Escherichia Coli"--with Manfred E. Bayer, 1965 (Box 39)
  - "A Technic for Preserving Structure in Specimens for Electron Microscope Studies: Stereoscopic Electron Microscopy"--Abstract, 1951 (Box 39)
  - "Techniques for the Preservation of Three-Dimensional Structure in Preparing Specimens for the Electron Microscope", [1951, [1982] (Box 39)
    -See also Ser.I, Institute for Scientific Information
    -See also Ser.VII, "Techniques for the Preservation of Three-Dimensional Structure in Preparing Specimens for the Electron Microscope"
  - "Techniques for Total War"--Lecture, [1947] (Box 39)
  - "The T-Even Bacteriophages", 1985; 2 folders (Box 39)
  - "The Theoretical Calculation of Intensities in the Vibrational Raman Effect", [1940]; 2 folders (Box 39)
  - "Thermodynamic Properties of Phosphorous Compounds"--with Don M. Yost, 1936 (Box 39)
  - "Tips of F Pili as Active Sites in E. Coli Mating"--with Jonathan T. Ou, [1971] (Box 39)
  - "Trichocysts in Paramecium: A Method of Isolation and Observations on Fine Structure"--with Susan C. Evans, [1964] (Box 39)
  - "Types of Morphology Found in Bacterial Viruses", 17 Nov. 1944 (Box 39)
    -See also Ser.II, Electron Microscope Society of America
  - Unidentified, 2 Jun. 1977; n.d.; 2 folders (Box 39)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 3 folders (Box 39)
    - Faculty Research Seminar, 3 May 1950 (Box 39)
    - Physics Colloquium, 9 Dec. 1942 (Box 39)
    - Trustees' Research Committee, n.d. (Box 39)
  - "The Use of Critical Point Phenomena in Preparing Specimens for the Electron Microscope", 1950 (Box 39)
  - "Virus Activity as Seen with the Electron Microscope", 2 Dec. 1954 (Box 40)
  - "Virus Reactions Inside of Bacterial Host Cells"--Abstract, 23 Nov. 1943 (Box 40)
  - "Virus Seminar Outline", n.d. (Box 40)
  - "Virus Symposium", [1954] (Box 40)
    -See also Ser.I, Electron Microscope Society of America, 22 Sep. 1954
  - "The Viruses"--Lecture, 13 Apr. 1951 (Box 40)
  - "Viruses Considered as Polyhedra and the Problem of Morphogenesis at the Molecular Level"--with André Lwoff, 1957 (Box 40)
    -See also Ser.IV, "Remarques sur les Caracteristiques de la Particule Virale Infectieuse"--with André Lwoff and François Jacob
- Series V. Works by others, 1933-1988; 4 boxes; 1.5 linear feet
  Articles, notes, reports, and abstracts written by colleagues and students of Anderson. Some authors are represented by two or more manuscripts, including Helen Gay, Hartmut Hoffmann-Berling, François Jacob, Andrzej W. Kozinski, Bruce R. Levin, Peter C. Nowell, Jonathan T. Ou, Lee D. Simon, Donald H. Walker, Jr., and Nobuto Yamamoto. Most of the works are scientific in nature, although there are two historical articles by Lily E. Kay. Any works that Anderson co-wrote with students and colleagues are filed in Series III alphabetically by title. Cross references are given for photographs that appear in this series.
  - "Chemical Inhibition of T Phages", 1 Oct. 1954; Adler, Alan (Box 41)
  - "Polyethylene Glycol-Induced Fusion of Heat Inactivated and Living Protoplasts of Bacillus Begaterium", [1978]; Alföldi, Lajos, Katalin Fodor, and Elvira Demiri (Box 41)
  - "Electron Microscope", 1941; Alyea, Hubert N. (Box 41)
  - "Variable Expression of Extracellular Polysaccharide in the Marine Bacterium Pseudomonas Atlantica Is Controlled by Genome Rearrangement", n.d.; Bartlett, Douglas H., Miriam E. Wright, and Michael Silverman (Box 41)
  - "Fast Responses of Bacterial Membranes to Virus Adsorption: A Fluorescence Study", 1980; Bayer, Manfred E. and Margret H. Bayer (Box 41)
  - "A Consistent Set of Values of the General Physical Constants", Aug. 1939; Birge, Raymond T., (Raymond Thayer), 1887-1980 (Box 41)
  - "A Study of Microcolonies of Escherichia Coli Using Time Lapse Photomicrography", [1959]; Borysko, Emil, Heiner Hoffman, and William Stylos (Box 41)
  - Examinations, 1951, 1953; Brill, Arthur S. (Box 41)
  - "Nascent Infectivity of Cofactor Requiring Coli-Phage T4", 1965-1966; Brown, Dennis Taylor, 1941- (Box 41)
  - "An Investigation of Genetic Exchange Between Recipient Strains of Escherichia Coli K-12", [1978]; Clark-Curtiss, Josephine E. and Raul M. Goldschmidt (Box 41)
  - "Isolation and Characterization of Temperature-Sensitive Mutants of Salmonella Typhimurium Bacteriophage P22", [196-]; Corcos, (Box 41)
  - "Electron Microscopy", n.d.; Cosslett, V.E. (Box 41)
  - International Phage Symposium--Summary for the Grantees of the National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis, 1952; Delbrück, Max (Box 41)
  - "The Intracellular Growth of Bacteriophage. I. Liberation of Intracellular Bacteriophage T4 by Premature Lysis with Another Phage or with Cyanide", [195-]; Doermann, A.H. (Box 41)
  - "The Status of Electron Microscopy on the Pacific Coast as of June 1953", Froula, H. (Box 41)
  - "Nucleo-Cytoplasmic Relations in Salivary-Gland Cells of Drosophila", 1955; Gay, Helen (Box 41)
  - "Serial Sections of Smears for Electron Microscopy", 1955; Gay, Helen (Box 41)
  - "Chromosome Transfer Between Escherichia Coli Hfr Strains and Proteus Mirabilis", Gemski, P., Jr., J.A. Wohlhieter, and L.S. Baron (Box 41)
  - "Structure of Type 5 Adenovirus I. Antigenic Relationship of Virus Structural Proteins to Virus-Specific Soluble Antigens from Infected Cells", [196-]; Ginsberg, Harold S. and Wesley C. Wilcox (Box 41)
    -See also Ser.IV, "Structure of Type 5 Adenovirus II. Fine..."
  - "Thymine Deficiency and the Deoxyribonucleic Acid Replication Cycle in Thymine Auxotrophs of Escherichia Coli", [195-]; Hanawalt, Philip C. and Ole Maaløe (Box 41)
  - "Cell-Cell Interactions in Conjugating Escherichia Coli: Purification of FPili with Biological Activity", n.d.; Helmuth, Reiner and Mark Achtman (Box 41)
  - "Nucleic Acid Free T2 Virus 'Ghosts' with Specific Biological Action", 1951; Herriott, Roger M. (Box 41)
  - "The Electron Optics of the Electron Microscope", [194-]; Hillier, James (Box 41)
  - "A Fibrous DNA Phage (fd) and a Spherical RNA Phage (fr) Specific for Male Strains of E. Coli. Part II. Physical Characteristics", [1962]; Hoffmann-Berling, Hartmut and D.A. Marvin (Box 41)
  - "Ein Fädiger DNS-Phage (fd) und Ein Sphärischer RNS-Phage (fr), Wirtsspezifisch Für Männliche Stämme von E. Coli. 1. Präparation und Chemische...", [1963]; Hoffmann-Berling, Hartmut, Don A. Marvin, and Hildegard Dürwald (Box 41)
  - "Ein Fädiger DNS-Phage (fd) und Ein Sphärischer RNS-Phage (fr), Wirtsspezifisch Für Männliche Stämme von E. Coli. 3. Biologisches Verhalten von fd und fr", [1963]; Hoffmann-Berling, Hartmut, Hildegard Dürwald, and Inge Beulke (Box 41)
  - "Physical and Chemical Studies on Isolated Pellicles of Parmecium Aurelia"--Thesis, 1967; Hufnagel, Linda Ann (Box 41)
  - "Accumulation of Newly Synthesized RNA Templates in a Unique Class of Polyribosomes During Embryogenesis", [1967]; Infante, Anthony A. and Martin Nemer (Box 42)
  - "Genetic and Physical Determinations of Chromosomal Segments in Escherichia Coli", 1957; Jacob, François and Elie L. Wollman (Box 42)
  - "Conjugation and Genetic Recombination in Escherichia Coli K-12", Jacob, François, Elie Wollman, and William Hayes (Box 42)
  - "Progress Report", n.d.; Kaji, H. (Box 42)
  - "The Role of Disulfide Pairing in the Biosynthesis of Antibody", 1960; Karush, Fred (Box 42)
  - "Conceptual Models and Analytical Tools: The Biology of Physicist Max Delbrück", 1985; Kay, Lily E. (Box 42)
  - "Cooperative Individualism and the Growth of Molecular Biology at the California Institute of Technology, 1928-1953", 1986; Kay, Lily E. (Box 42)
  - "Electromagnetophoresis Experiments", 23 Oct. 1958; Keiper, David A. (Box 42)
  - "Early Intracellular Events in the Replication of T4 Phage DNA III. Random Utilization of Phage Coded Enzymes by Simultaneously Infecting Phage", [1967]; Kozinski, Andrzej W. and Patti b. Kozinski (Box 42)
  - "Replicative T4 Phage DNA; Preferential Adsorption of Replicative Moiety into the Interphase Pellet During Phenol Extraction", [1965]; Kozinski, Andrzej W. and T.H. Lin (Box 42)
  - "Early Intracellular Events in the Replication of T4 Phage DNA", [1965]; Kozinski, Andrzej W., T.H. Lin, and P.B. Kozinski (Box 42)
  - "Genetic Heterogeneity of Rabbit Alpha-1-Antitrypsin", [1983]; Kueppers, Friedrich, C.C. Lee, R.R. Fox, and J.K. Mills (Box 42)
  - "Oil Lenses on Water and the Nature of Monomolecular Expanded Films", 1933; Langmuir, Irving, 1881-1957 (Box 42)
  - "Cell Fusion with E. Coli Cells", 1977; Lévi, Corinne (Box 42)
  - "The Population Biology of Bacterial Plasmids: A Priori Conditions for the Existence of Conjugationally Transmitted Factors", Levin, Bruce R. and Frank M. Stewart (Box 42)
  - "Resource Limited Growth, Competition, and Predation: A Model and Experimental Studies with Bacteria and Bacteriophage", Levin, Bruce R., Frank M. Stewart, and Lin Chao (Box 42)
  - "A Complex Community in a Simple Habitat: An Experimental Study with Bacteria and Phage", Levin, Bruce R., Lin Chao, and Frank M. Stewart (Box 42)
  - "T4 Phage-Mediated Release of Envelope Components from E. Coli", 1972-1973; Loeb, Marilyn Rosenthal, 1930- (Box 42)
    -See also Ser.I, Biochimica et Biophysica Acta
  - "Inversion of Transfer Modes and Low Integration of Early Markers in Conjugation in Escherichia Coli"--Thesis, 1965; Low, Kenneth Brooks, Jr. (Box 42)
  - "Tubular and Polyhedral Packing of Spheres", Luckman, Gregory and Ralph O. Erickson (Box 42)
  - "Mutations of Bacteria and of Bacteriophage", 1965; Luria, S. E., (Salvador Edward), 1912-1991 (Box 42)
  - "Classification and Nomenclature of Viruses--The Principles", [196-]; Lwoff, André, 1902- (Box 42)
  - "PKS, a New RAF Related Sequence in Man", n.d.; Mark, George E., Todd W. Seeley, Thomas B. Shows, and John D. Mountz (Box 42)
  - "Technique and Applications of the Replication of Frozen Solutions for Electron Microscopy"--Abstract, 1953; Meryman, Harold T. (Box 42)
  - "T4 Bacteriophage: The Mechanism of Contraction of the Tail Sheath", 1966; Moody, Michael F. (Box 42)
  - "Structural Differentiation within the Bacterial Cell", 1940; Mudd, Stuart and David B. Lackman (Box 42)
  - "Fat Derivatives, Especially Lecithin", [193-]; Myers, R.J. (Box 42)
  - "Chromosome Studies in Human Leukemia"--Abstract, [196-]; Nowell, Peter C. and David A. Hungerford (Box 42)
  - "DNA Measurements of Chromosomes, Including the Philadelphia Chromosome, in Human Chronic Granulocytic Leukemia"--Abstract, 1962; Nowell, Peter C., G.T. Rudkin, and David A. Hungerford (Box 42)
  - "How Water-Soluble Polymers May Promote Fusion of Cells", [1979]; Ogston, Alexander G. (Box 42)
  - "In Vitro Studies on the Gene 21 Dependent Proteolysis of Several Proteins Involved in the Head Morphogenesis of Bacteriophage T4"--Thesis. Folder #1, 1975; Onorato, Louise C. (Box 42)
  - "In Vitro Studies on the Gene 21 Dependent Proteolysis of Several Proteins Involved in the Head Morphogenesis of Bacteriophage T4"--Thesis. Folder #2, 1975; Onorato, Louise C. (Box 42)
  - "Effect of Zn2+ on Bacterial Conjugation: II. Increase in Ability of F- Cells to Form Mating Pairs", 1971-1972; Ou, Jonathan T. (Box 42)
    -See also Ser.IV, "Effect of Zn2+ on Bacterial Conjugation: I. Inhibition of Mating Pair Formation"--with Jonathan T. Ou
  - "Location of F Pili Gene and Differences in HfrH and HfrC"--Abstract, 1971; Ou, Jonathan T. (Box 42)
  - "Specific Insertion and Deletion of IS1-Like DNA Element Causes the Reversible Expression of the Virulence (Vi) Capsular Antigen of Critrobacter Freundii in Escherichia Coli", 1988; Ou, Jonathan T., Louis Baron, Fran A. Rubin, and Dennis J. Kopecko (Box 42)
  - "Patterns and Controls of Galactose Utilization by Streptococcus Faecalis Ioci", Apr. 1963; Pakman, Leonard M. (Box 43)
  - "Assay of Infectious RNA from Bacteriophage R 17", [196-]; Paranchych, W. (Box 43)
  - "Pictures of Bacterial Forms Taken with the Electron Microscope", 1940; Polevitzky, Katherine (Box 43)
  - "A Study of an Ultraviolet Light Absorbing Material Released by Escherichia Coli on Infection with T2 or T4 Bacteriophage"--Thesis, 1951; Prater, Charles Dwight (Box 43)
  - "Structure and Biological Activity of v-raf, a New Oncogene Transduced by a Retrovirus", Rapp, U.R., M.D. Goldsborough, G.E. Mark, et al. (Box 43)
  - "Heterogeneity of Generation Number Among Cells in Diploid Fibroblast Cultures", Rigney, David R. (Box 43)
  - "The Effect of Urea on Cofactor Requiring Bacteriophage"--Thesis, 1956; Sato, Gordon Hisashi (Box 43)
  - "T4 Polyheads"--Abstract, n.d.; Simon, Lee D. (Box 43)
  - "A Bacterial Mutation Affecting T4 Phage DNA Synthesis and Tail Production", Simon, Lee D. and Dale Snover (Box 43)
  - "Lambda Head Morphogenesis: Studies on the Role of DNA", n.d.; Simon, Lee D., P. Dawson, and A. Skalka (Box 43)
  - "Activation of Herpes Type Virus Synthesis in Burkitt Lymphoma Cells by Ultraviolet Irradiation", [1972]; Stephens, Richard, F. Durr, K. Traul, and G. Heberlein (Box 43)
  - "Iron-Binding Proteins, Hepatitis B Virus, and Cancer in Taiwan", 1984; Stevens, Richard G., R. Palmer Beasley, and Baruch S. Blumberg (Box 43)
  - "Sequence Homology Between tRNA and rRNA of E. Coli and the Transcriptive Origin of the -CCA Terminal of tRNA", [1967]; Suyama, Yoshitaka (Box 43)
  - "Chromosomal Clustering of Five Defined Endogenous Retrovirus Loci in White Leghorn Chickens", Tereba, Allan and Susan M. Astrin (Box 43)
  - "Some Unusual Properties of the Nucleic Acid in Bacteriophages S 13 and 0X174", [1958]; Tessman, Irwin (Box 43)
  - "Plasmid Stability and Biomass Production: Comparison Between Free and Immobilized Cell Cultures of Escherichia Coli BZ18/pTG 201, without Selection Pressure", [1984]; Thomas, Daniel, Philippe De Taxis du Poët, Pascal Dhulster, and Jean-Noel Barbotin (Box 43)
  - "Appendix: Bacteriophage T4 Head Models Based on Icosahedral Symmetry", [1972]; Walker, Donald H., Jr. and G. Mosig (Box 43)
  - "Structure and Function of Bacteriophage P1 and Its Morphological Variants"--Abstract, Walker, Donald H., Jr., author and Thomas F. Anderson, supervisor (Box 43)
  - "A Vitamin D-Induced Calcium Binding Protein, a Possible Transepithelial Carrier", [1967]; Wasserman, R.H. (Box 43)
  - "College Courses in Electron Microscopy", 1952; Weber, Robert L. (Box 43)
  - "Progressive Adhesion of a String Vibrating Against a Plane", [1952]; Weinstein, Marvin A. (Box 43)
  - "Mutagenesis During in Vitro DNA Synthesis". Folder #1, 1977; Weymouth, Lisa (Box 43)
  - "Mutagenesis During in Vitro DNA Synthesis". Folder #2, 1977; Weymouth, Lisa (Box 43)
  - "Elektronenmikroskopische Untersuchungen der Innenstrukturen Kernloser Erythrocyten. I. Retikulocyten und Pseudoreticulocyten", [1955]; Wolpers, Carl (Box 44)
  - "Genetic Evolution of Bacteriophage I. Hybrids Between Unrelated Bacteriophages P22 and Fels 2", [1968]; Yamamoto, Nobuto (Box 44)
  - "Genetic Evolution of Bacteriophage II. Physical Length of the Homologous Region in a Hybrid Between Serologically and Morphologically Unrelated Phages", [1970]; Yamamoto, Nobuto and Hiroto Akiyoshi (Box 44)
  - "The Raman Spectrum of Boron Trifluoride", 1937; Yost, Don M. (Box 44)
    -See also Ser.IV, "The Raman Spectrum of Boron Trifluoride Gas"
  - "Chromosomal Regulation of Sexual Expression in E. Coli", 1978; Zinder, Norton D. and Terry J. Lerner (Box 44)
- Series VI. Research Notes and Notebooks, 1931-1977; 6 boxes; 2.75 linear feet
  Loose notes and notebooks that are arranged by folder title and include notes from experiments (e.g, "Growth Requirements of T2, T4A, T6"); notes taken by Anderson at Cold Spring Harbor and at other symposia; and course notes from Anderson's days at California Institute of Technology (e.g., "Atomic Physics"). Notebooks with no title have been filed as "Unidentified--Notebook." Some notebooks have loose notes that are larger than the notebook pages. These notes were placed in the same folder as the notebook but at the end of the folder. A photocopy of the first sheet of notes was placed at the appropriate notebook page with a cross reference to the end of the folder.
  - "Atomic and Molecular Spectra" (Box 45)
  - "Atomic Physics", 1931-1934 (Box 45)
  - "Bacterial Stocks"--Notebook, n.d. (Box 45)
  - "Bilateral Symmetry", n.d. (Box 45)
  - Biophysics Course by Hans Borei--Notes, 1950-1951; 2 folders (Box 45)
  - "Books on Electron Microscope", 1945-1946 (Box 45)
  - "Calculation of Atomic Cross Sections in the Electron Microscope", n.d. (Box 45)
  - "Calculation of Results for KCl Prism"--Notebook, [193-] (Box 45)
  - "Chemical and Statistical Thermodynamics", 1940 (Box 45)
  - "Chemosterilants", 17 Mar. 1962 (Box 45)
  - "Chicago Meeting", Nov. 1942 (Box 45)
  - "Clumping Experiments", 1938 (Box 45)
  - "Coiling in Snails", n.d. (Box 45)
  - "Cold Spring Harbor", 1944, 1957
  - "Cold Spring Harbor"--Notebook, 1961 (Box 45)
  - "Colloque de Royaumont II", 1958 (Box 46)
  - "Colored Plaques", n.d. (Box 46)
  - "Comments on 'Electron Microscopy of Polio-Myelitis Viruses - Method of Specimen Preparation' by Taylor and McCormick" (Box 46)
  - "Comparison of Virus Assays on Difco Nutrient and Ammonium Lactate Media" (Box 46)
  - "Comparison of Wilhelmy Method with Film Balance", n.d. (Box 46)
  - "Conjugation of Bacteria", n.d. (Box 46)
  - "Coulter Counter", 1973 (Box 46)
  - "CsCL Prism D. with Brom-Naphthaline"--Notebook, 1933 (Box 46)
  - [Cultures]--Notebook, 1958, 1963 (Box 46)
  - "Determination of Height of Object by Shadowcasting", 1946 (Box 46)
  - "Effect of Radiation on Phage, Yeast", 1939-1946 (Box 46)
  - [Electron Microscope Experiments], 1954-1955 (Box 46)
  - [Electron Microscope Experiments]--Notebook, 1938-1939 (Box 46)
  - "Elements of Quantum Theory", [193-] (Box 46)
  - "Elmiskop I. Log Book #1"--Notebook, 1959-1961 (Box 46)
  - "Elmiskop I. Log Book #2"--Notebook, 1961-1968 (Box 47)
  - [Experiments], 1943-1944 (Box 47)
  - [Experiments]--Notebook, 1937-1953 (Box 47)
  - [Experiments with P22], n.d. (Box 47)
  - "Group Theory"--Notebook, n.d. (Box 47)
  - "Growth Requirements of T2, T4A, T6", 1944-1945 (Box 47)
  - "H-Bond Vibs. in Subst. Acids" (Box 47)
  - [Hfr Experiments]--Notebook, 1955-1957 (Box 47)
  - "Inorg. Chem. Lab."--Notebook, 1931-1932 (Box 47)
  - "Introduction to Mathematical Physics", [193-] (Box 47)
  - "Log ETEC"--Notebook, 1975-1977 (Box 48)
  - "Lysis of Br10 by T4A, T6, BV", 1945 (Box 48)
  - "Lysogenic vs. Lytic Cycle of Phage Multiplication", 1953 (Box 48)
  - "Math"--Notebook, n.d. (Box 48)
  - "Models Involving Indestructable Plasmids" (Box 48)
  - "Molecular Structure of the Cofactors for the Bacterial Virus T4", 1946, 1949 (Box 48)
  - "Nashville Meeting", 1947 (Box 48)
  - "National Academy of Sciences Meeting. Pedigrees of Exconj. in E. Coli K-12", 1957 (Box 48)
  - "Non-Relativistic Quantum Mechanics". Folder #1--Notebook, 1936 (Box 48)
  - "Non-Relativistic Quantum Mechanics". Folder #2, n.d. (Box 48)
  - "Notes on Physical Properties of Solutions; Diary on E.M. Studies"--Notebook, 7 Oct. 1936-26 Jun. 1941 (Box 48)
  - "Notes on Work of Various People"--Notebook, 26 Sep. 1957-27 Jun. 1958 (Box 48)
  - "Nouvelle Théorie de L'Action Capillaire" by Poisson--Notes, n.d. (Box 48)